你的设备的无线电传输大概是这个样子
The cell radio in your device operates roughly like this.
从初始的空闲状态到能传输数据的状态
From an initial idle state, it takes a couple of seconds
要花费大概2秒钟
to turn on until it can start transmitting. That kind of
经常触发这个延迟会降低用户体验
latency makes for a sucky web browsing experience. So rather than
所以比起来不传输数据立马回到空闲状态，状态机采用了
going back to idle, state machine stays on at full power
在这之后仍然处于满功率状态一段时间，通常是5~10秒
for a certain amount of time. Typically, around five to ten
然后下降到一个较低功率的中间状态
seconds before dropping to an intermediate low power mode that uses
这时候用的电也比满功率少，要回到满功率
less battery than full power, and has lower latency to return
所需的延迟时间也比空闲状态少
to full power than the standby mode. If a new
如果新开启了一个网络连接，状态机会回到满功率状态
transfer is initiated, the radio will be promoted back to
如果之后30秒~1分钟的时间没事可做
full power mode. And if nothing happens for another period
of time, typically around 30 seconds to a minute, it'll
它会回到空闲状态。确切的延迟和后续时间（tail time）
drop back to standby. The exact latency and tail times
不同的载体网络不同，甚至不同国家和州都不同
varies between carriers, and even in carriers between states and
因为他们都试着平衡两者，使得有最低延迟和
countries, as they try to balance low latency with longer
最长的电池寿命，这些都要考虑到
battery life based on factors like cell congestion and typical
像网络状况和拥挤程度诸如此类。所以确切的时间是变化的
prevailing network conditions. So the exact timings vary. How
那么我们怎么优化我们的传输频率呢？
do we optimize our transfer frequency? Ultimately, it doesn't matter
其实这并不需要知道确切的时间值
what the specific timings are. You just need to
你只需要知道网络是在试图去
understand that the network is going to attempt to balance
平衡低延迟和高电池寿命。对于我们来说
low latency with high battery life. For us, when
计划数据传输的时候
it comes to planning out data transfers, we really like
我们通常是在这
to be somewhere around here,. Now, if we return
我们回到无线电波状态机看看
briefly to the cell radio state machine, we know that
每当我们开始数据传输，这个无线电
every time we perform a data transfer, the radio will
会至少保持5秒钟的满功率后续时间
stay active for at least another five seconds of full tail
和30秒~1分钟的低功率的后续时间
time, and anywhere from 30 seconds to a minute at low
才能回到空闲状态。这意味着每当你
power before it finally returns to standby. That means every time
开启一个新的传输，你至少要开启无线电20秒
you initiate a transfer, you're powering the cell radio up for
我们来看看这对App有什么影响
at least 20 seconds. So let's take a look at how
that affects an app, using the little cookie approach. An app
这样的App消耗电量很快
like this can drain the battery without even having to transfer
这些小峰表示
much data. Each of these small peaks is
App每隔15秒把分析数据传回服务器
an app pinging its analytics back to the server,.
这些大峰表示
In this case, every 15 seconds. These logi-peaks represent
用户交互引起的间断的数据传输
intermittent data transfers based on user interaction. For example,
比如用户可能在看餐馆的列表
they may be viewing a restaurant listing or looking
或者查看明天的天气预报。下面，我们画出了
at tomorrow's weather forecast. Beneath it, we've graphed how
无线状态图。蓝色的表示数据传输
this affects the radio state. The blue shows active
红色的表示处于满功率
data transfers. The red, the radio in full power.
黄色表示处于低功率。中间的缺口，
And yellow showing low power mode. The gaps in between, if
如果有的话，代表空闲状态
there were any, indicate when the radio was idle. So while
所以当这个App运行时，无线电状态为空闲状态的时间
this app is running, what is the percentage of time that
占百分比多少？
the cell radio is able to go back to its idle state?